Today we will learn how to use the Automatic Clothing Tool.
For example, when the model is the default model of CLO,
when the costume is completed,
and the model size needs to be adjusted or the horse is made,
how to automatically wear 3D costume for the virtual model?
This is a file with code information.
Click on the 3D model in the window of the object to match the 3D model.
Select the model of the corresponding size in the folder.
Click on the Automatic Clothing Tool in the 3D tool bar.
You can see that the costume is completed very quickly according to the model size.
The remaining two horses are also the same operation.
Change the size of the object window and match the 3D shape.
Click on the Automatic Clothing Tool in the 3D tool bar.
In this way, you can quickly complete the costume cladding corresponding to the size.
Next is the last size.
It is the same as the previous operation.
In this way, you can quickly complete the production of this horse-riding file.
In the menu bar, find Production and select Check Horse.
Now you can see the cladding effect of each size in one page.
Example 2. When you need to use an external model,
the external model cannot use the Automatic Clothing Tool directly.
You need to match the 3D model with the costume first.
In the menu bar, find the virtual model and select the virtual model editor.
In the top of the virtual model editor, find the costume cladding.
There are two ways to create a costume.
First, you can try the Automatic Clothing Tool.
In the upper right corner, click the Automatic Clothing Tool button.
You can see that there is a gray version shadow around the model.
Click the Automatic Clothing Tool button at the bottom.
Rotate to see if the red costume cladding around the model is flat.
In this way, the costume cladding of the model is completed.
If the costume cladding is not created correctly,
then you need to use the manual creation.
You need to draw a line on the model according to the instructions on the mouse.
First, draw a neckline.
Draw three dots on the neck.
Next is the neckline.
It is also the same creation method.
Follow the same method to complete the rest of the parts.
Click the
Automatically create a costume cladding on the bottom of the list.
Click on the button below the list to create a costume cladding.
You can complete the manual creation of the costume cladding.
After the creation is completed, click Save.
You can save the model with the costume cladding.
Now let's see how to replace the model.
Open the model directly.
You can use the switch to switch the model.
In the 3D tool bar, click on Automatic Clothing
Now this model has been replaced
Click on Automatic Clothing